#### gordontrinder@gmail.com

# GORDON TRINDER

Project info available @ www.gordomakesthings.com

Versatile engineer with experience in firmware, software, and hardware development for socially and environmentally driven technologies. Comfortable in fast-paced startup environments, with a hands-on approach to problem-solving, leadership, and multidisciplinary collaboration.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Senior Embedded Systems Engineer

Vertical Future | August 2022 - Present

- Developed and integrated control software for automated vertical farm machinery, including seeders, conveyors and robots for moving plants between processes
- Led and expanded the Embedded Systems team from 2 to 5 engineers, managing workload, mentoring staff, and coordinating projects to transition from isolated machines to a fully integrated farm for food production and trials.
- Wrote mid-level control software in Python, interfacing with farm subsystems via RS485, Modbus, and RPC.
- Conducted onsite testing and technical support; covering wiring, software validation, network setup, and maintenance
- Managed PCB production, maintained server, defined subsystem requirements, and improved engineering processes.

#### **Mechatronics Engineer**

ALP Technologies | April 2021 - July 2022

- Developed mechanical, electronic and software features for smart, scalable battery system to be deployed in lowincome countries
- Delivered client project: Full circuit and Altium PCB design for IoT sensing device, including board assembly and testing
- IoT firmware and software development using C++/Python to interface with edge devices via MQTT.

#### **EDUCATION**

Distinction

2:1

MsC Applied Mechatronic Engineering Harper Adams University | 2019

MEng Electrical & Electronics Engineering
University of Edinburgh | 2013 - 2018

### SKILLS & PROFICIENCIES

SW/FW Development   [Python/C++]
Circuit design and PCB layout
Hardware prototyping
Engineering management

#### INTERESTS

- Cooking
- Cycling
- Dancing
- Repair Clothes, Electronics, DIY, Bikes

## **AUTOMATION & HARDWARE ENGINEER**